# Daniel Skowroński

@ daniel@skowron.ski

% blog.dsinf.net

in linkedin.com/in/daniel-skowronski

O github.com/danielskowronski

# **ABOUT ME**

My main fields of interest (both professionally and as a hobby) are systems architecture, administration, computer networks and cybersecurity. I refer to myself as hacker (in the original meaning of that word, but also as whitehat researcher).

I have experience in many stages of computer system lifecycle - not only in typical business roles but also as full-stack freelancer as well as all-in-one IT guy on festivals and in students' association. That gives me the advantage of being able to understand customer and business needs and manage resources (including time) with care. Another aspect of my career story - work in operations jobs allowed me to learn how to work under time pressure in disaster scenarios.

I'm advocating Bill Gate's words "I choose a lazy person to do a hard job because a lazy person will find an easy way to do it" - and really prefer to automate everything. I'm also a constant learner - not only mastering current skills, but also discovering new approaches and technologies.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Site Reliability Engineer, Cloud Engineer

## **Grand Parade part of William Hill**

July 2020 - Ongoing

**♥** Krakow, Poland

I'm building tools and processes to ensure the reliability and availability of a private cloud that supports online gambling and gaming and processes Big Data. The technology stack includes on-premise Linux VMs (VMware vSphere), Docker containers (Apache Mesos, Marathon), AWS cloud (EKS and EC2), Apache Airflow, Sonatype Nexus and Gitlab. Infrastructure-as-a-Code paradigm is supported by Puppet and Terraform. I'm also part of on-call support that responds 24/7 to incidents within the platform.

#### Senior DevOps Engineer

#### **Prescient Co**

**M** October 2019 - July 2020

My job was to be a bridge between Development and IT Operations departments - maintaining systems to keep High Availability and security together with meeting business goals. Important parts of this chapter in my career are implementing Infrastructure-as-a-Code paradigm, introducing new operating system (Linux) and containerization systems (Kubernetes) into the existing ecosystem.

# Linux Platform Engineer

## **Motorola Solutions Systems**

May 2019 - October 2019

As software developer in Dimetra Platform team, I was responsible for the development of management and deployment tools for Linux platforms, as well as virtualization using VMware and KVM solutions.

I was also responsible for the lab environment.

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

Linux Ansible Python Networks Terraform AWS



# **STRENGTHS**

Development

Python bash PowerShell awk

Perl SQL Go C# x86 assembly

MTEX JavaScript

Virtualization and containerization

VMware vSphere KVM (libvirt)

Docker LXC Kubernetes

• DevOps/automation tools

Ansible Puppet Jenkins Gitlab CI
Azure Pipelines Elasticsearch
Grafana NewRelic

Cloud

Terraform AWS VMware Cloud

Databases

 ${f (MSSQL)} {f (MySQL)} {f (PostgreSQL)}$ 

# **EDUCATION**

Computer Science

Jagiellonian University in Cracow

**2014 - 2016** 

# **LANGUAGES**

Polish English



# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

## **Platform Operations Engineer**

#### **Akamai Technologies**

**I** July 2016 - May 2019

Y Krakow, Poland

My responsibilities in Network Operations Command Center included responding to real-time issues with the entire Akamai platform - from routine hardware problems to global routing or capacity incidents which require immediate action. I participated in maintaining general network health, resolving configuration defects, performing network maintenance works and responding to outside communication with other NOCs and service providers.

Since 2018 I worked on senior level assignments which included approving potentially dangerous nonstandard operations, being part of incident coordination and deploying configuration changes. I also developed several software solutions that helped multiple departments in everyday work.

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

## System Administrator

#### Computer Science Students' Association - KSI UJ

December 2014 - January 2018

**◊** Krakow, Poland

My role as SysAdmin was to keep our network working and secure, maintain servers belonging to KSI including critical infrastructure (mail, DNS), develop applications that were used by the management board, and supervise the server room.

Another task of Administrator in KSI was to cooperate with network administrators of university.

#### Secretary of the Board

#### Computer Science Students' Association - KSI UJ

For 2 academic years I was also Secretary of the Board in KSI. As active member of board, I also participated in organizing various events on UJ like *Malopolska Noc Naukowców* (Night of Scientists) and *Festiwal Nauki* (Science Festival).

#### Chief Information Officer

#### **Academic IT Festival - SFI**

math display="block" December 2014 - July 2017" December 2014 - July 2017

**◊** Krakow, Poland

I was member of logistics team, Chief Information Officer and web developer involved in development of contest application (PHP, later Erlang) and DevOps (Git, CI).

I also acted as SysAdmin, being responsible for network infrastructure during the event and helpdesk engineer dealing with end users.

#### **IT Coordinator**

## Theatre Festival "Zwierciadla"

🛗 September 2012 - May 2014

♥ Lublin, Poland

"Zwierciadla" is a high school theater festival organized by students. Since 2013 I was responsible for its website and other IT and logistics related tasks like network configuration, helpdesk, coordinating multimedia processing and publishing etc.

That experience gave me an early opportunity to learn team work and responsibility in the face of deadlines.

# **OTHERS**

- Layer2 and Layer3 network maintenance and management (Cisco, Juniper, HP)
- TCP/IP and higher level protocols debugging (Wireshark)
- security & whitehat hacking
- electronics

## INTERESTS

- cybersecurity (whitehat-hacking)
- embedded systems
- electronics
- cloud computing
- amateur photography
- Japanese culture

# **GDPR**

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the European Parliament's and Council of the European Union Regulation on the Protection of Natural Persons as of 27 April 2016, with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (Data Protection Directive)